



# **Bahadir Omer Cakmak**

(+49) 17662798451

Date of birth: 27/08/1999

Email address: <a href="mailto:bahadir0646@gmail.com">bahadir0646@gmail.com</a>

**Website:** https://cakmak.netlify.app

GitHub:: <a href="https://github.com/bomercakmak">https://github.com/bomercakmak</a>

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/bahadir-omer-cakmak-4b4036204

### **ABOUT ME**

I am a **Full Stack Engineer** with more than 3 years of experience. Since the beginning of my programming journey, I have been focusing on expanding my knowledge and abilities in software engineering, programming and quality assurance with a special emphasis in web technologies. I frequently use popular web technologies including, but not limited to, **HTML5**, **CSS**, **Bootstrap**, **JavaScript**, **TypeScript**, **PHP**, **Node.js**, **Express.js**, **React**, **Redux**, **Next.js**, **MongoDB**, **Firebase**. By various internships that I have made, I am always trying to excel my communication and organizational abilities with resourceful approach to solving diverse problems.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Full Stack Engineer**

**Collabera** [ 01/10/2021 - Current ]

- Working as a Full Stack Engineer for S&P Global, one of the largest business and financial analytics companies in USA and becoming an active member of a cross-functional software development team that specializes in performance improvement.
- Using powerful technologies, such as JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Next, Redux, Node.js, in a very specific, complex, and detailed manner; creating high value and efficient performance.
- Research, analysis and high-level implementation of some of the latest and most critical web development techniques, such as server-side, client-side, and progressive rendering, including rehydration and parti al hydration; thus, gaining invaluable experience in both theoretical and practical aspects of these techniques.
- Playing highly significant role in the development of a software with a Micro Front-End architecture by means of using and implementing Micro Front-End features and Microservices.
- Having a professional experience in the development of single page applications, software engineering and performance improvement; writing clean and understandable code and documentation by using best practices.
- Writing comprehensive **Unit test** for every **user story** or **feature** that is being created and implemented.

# **Full Stack Engineer Intern**

**BCS-IT GmbH** [ 01/06/2021 - 01/10/2021 ]

Location: Langenfeld, Germany

- SaleVali Integrated Multi-Channel E-Commerce Web application.
- Successfully generated front-end programming utilizing HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Redux-Saga, Formik, npm, and various other third-party libraries.
- Designed and implemented back-end system using a variety of programming languages and web technologies including: **Node.js**, **PHP**, **Loopback**, **MongoDB**, **RESTful API**.
- Integrated several software to the development process using **Agile** methodology (**Scrum**): **Git, Gitflow, Bi tbucket,** and **Jira**.
- Attended daily **Scrum** meetings, **Sprint planning and reviews**, communicated with other developers and managers, come up with creative solutions.
- Developed, maintained, and tested **React-based** complex and large web applications.

**Supervisor Feedback:** Omer was a successful, all-round trainee that made significant contributions to his projects. He has featly completed the required assignments on a timely manner, and helped the team to carry the project to the next level. Having demonstrated the required skills to get promoted to a Full Stack Web Developer position, he was meticulous and determined to accomplish his goals. It was a great pleasure for me and the other team members to work with him. I would recommend Omer to every passionate team that is looking towards a fresh web developer with extensive experience.

# **Software Engineer Intern**

**Mibgate GmbH** [ 01/07/2020 - 01/10/2020 ]

**Location**: Düsseldorf, Germany

- Used development tools HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, React, TypeScript, and
- **Node.js** on regular basis.
- Supported software engineering projects in **Agile** work environment
- Handled scripting tasks for debugging and automation using **Cypress**.
- · Collaborated with product team members to implement new feature developments.
- Partnered with company mentor to learn **best practices** in software design.

**Supervisor Feedback:** Our intern Bahadır Omer Cakmak worked based on Web development. He used recent and industry wide technologies that are popularly used in the software engineering and web development community thoroughly. He has expanded his programming skills by working hard daily on real life programming challenges. He has given various speeches at the daily meeting, which has improved his public speaking and communication skills.

### **Software Engineer Intern**

**AnyWork GmbH** [ 01/07/2019 - 01/10/2019 ]

**Location**: Düsseldorf, Germany

- Created interactive websites with software development department using **JavaScript** and **React**
- framework.
- Worked alongside product managers to re-architect a multi-page web app into a single page web-app
- built in **React**.
- Fixed bugs from existing websites and implemented enhancements that significantly improved web
- functionality and performance.

**Supervisor Feedback:** The trainee can achieve to applications development, projects and website development. Trainer can work as a part of a team with cooperation. Trainee can be able to work with JavaScript and React on Front-end Development. Monitoring international activities and working as a team member to software development and project development.

# **Social Media Manager**

Heremood GmbH [ 08/2018 - 06/2019 ]

Location: Cologne, Germany

- Designed and executed global social media selling strategy across 125,000 followers on Store's Website,
   Amazon, Ebay, Etsy, Instagram, and Facebook.
- Regularly used technologies to sell product on store website; **Wordpress, Shopify, BigCommerce, Google Analytics, Google Ads** and **GoDaddy**.
- Technologies used regularly to create social media posts, videos and blogs: **Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Premiere Pro, Final Cut Pro, DaVinci Resolve, Microsoft Office 365** and **Canva**.
- Provided digital marketing solutions to Amazon FBA / FBM businesses

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

# **Bachelor of Computer Engineering**

Vistula University [ 01/09/2018 - 01/03/2022 ]

- Graduated with a high GPA of **4.37** out of 5.
- Professional specialization on Web Technologies Engineering.
- Member of Computer Engineering Club.
- **Mentor** in the university's mentoring program.

# **English Language Preparatory Program**

**Cankaya University** [ 01/09/2017 - 01/06/2018 ]

# **High School Diploma**

Acı High School

#### **LANGUAGE SKILLS**

Mother tongue(s): Turkish

Other language(s):

#### **English**

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1
SPOKEN INTERACTION C1

German

LISTENING A1 READING A1 WRITING A1

**SPOKEN INTERACTION A1** 

#### **Azerbaijani**

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1
SPOKEN INTERACTION C1

#### **CONFERENCES AND SEMINARS**

### **JunctionX Budapest Hackathon 2019**

[Budapest, Hungary]

https://www.hackathon.com/event/junctionx-budapest-2019-5d35791d2e538f001c438cbe

# **Google Digital Marketing 2019**

[ Ankara, Turkey ]

# **Hack Yeah Hackathon Warsaw 2018**

[ Warsaw, Poland ] <a href="https://hackyeah.pl/">https://hackyeah.pl/</a>

# **PROJECTS**

#### SaleVali

[06/2021 - 10/2021]

SaleVali is **React-based** web application that aims to integrate various E-Commerce and Shipping platforms, in a single page web application. The main goal of the application is to have a single, user-friendly environment for online-retailers, resolving the hassle and complexity of selling products, managing invoice, checking stocks, and tracking customers, in a variety of platforms.

#### **Ahsen**

[09/2020 - 06/2021]

Ahsen is an **Order Management System (OMS)** for wholesaler. An order management system (OMS) is a digital way to manage the lifecycle of an order. It tracks all the information and processes, including order entry, inventory management, fulfillment and after-sales service. An OMS offers visibility to both the business and the buyer. Organizations can have near real-time insight into inventories and customers can check when an order will arrive.

#### **COVID-19 Tracker**

[05/2020 - 06/2020]

This project created for to draw attention to COVID-19 and make the world better and healthier.

• I have many more projects. You can access my projects on my <u>Personal Website</u> or <u>GitHub account</u>.

#### **HOBBIES AND INTERESTS**

#### **Table Tennis**

I played professional table tennis for 2 years. I have 1 city championship in table tennis. I'm just playing as a hobby right now.

### Hiking

As a software engineer, we can stay still for a long time because we spend so much time on the computer. Therefore, it is a very good hobby to Hiking regularly

#### **SKILLS**

# Software Engineering & Full Stack Web Development

HTML - CSS - Sass - Responsive Design - Bootstrap - JavaScript - PHP - Python - TypeScript - npm - Node.js - React - Next.js - Redux - React Router - Material-UI - Express.js - Asynchronous Programming - Firebase - MongoDB - MyS QL - Git - Gitflow Workflow - GitHub - Bitbucket - Agile - Scrum - Jira

### Social Media & E-Commerce

Microsoft Office 365 - Wordpress - Shopify - BigCommerce - Google Ads - Adobe Photoshop - Adobe Premiere Pro - Final Cut Pro - DaVinci Resolve - Canva

#### Soft Skills

Problem Solving - Critical Thinking - Communication - Teamwork - Creativity - Time Management - Visual Thinking - Work Ethics - Adaptability